COURTNEY MCRAE

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT



310-962-1420



courtneymcrae9@gmail.com



Los Angeles, CA



www.courtneymcrae.com



github.com/courtneymcrae

linkedin.com/in/courtneymcrae

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSION

General Assembly II Santa Monica II 2016

Over the course of 12 weeks, I completed over 480 hours of instruction, leaping into web application development - From wire framing, data modeling, prototyping, to deployment. While being introduced to different programming languages, libraries, and frameworks, I created projects that demonstrate my ability and knowledge to take concepts from class and implement them into working applications.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Ruby

Web-Application Frameworks: Node.js + Express, Rails

Front-end libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap

Front-end frameworks: Angular

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

CSS precompilers: SaSS

Version Control: Git and Github

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Prior to developing websites I was a real estate assistant to a top producing team at Keller Williams Santa Monica. This experience taught me not only how to be a resourceful team player and have excellent communication skills but also how to be detail oriented, perform in high pressure situations, and have positive experiences working with clients. I worked on a team with four others and was the go to person for all principals. It was there that I learned my business skills. Becoming a web developer has allowed me to merge these two areas; my past business skills with my passion to create.

EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER

Hermosa Swim II Hermosa Beach II 2017 - Present

- Designed a fully responsive clean and modern website.
- Wrote creative product descriptions and designed Lookbook pages.
- Made business accounts on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and Pinterest to promote marketing and grow target audience followers.
- Established and expanded a list of email subscribers and sent out well designed marketing emails.

DEVELOPER & MARKETING

Homes From Jan II Hermosa Beach II 2016 - 2018

- Designed an elegant and clean fully responsive Wordpress website.
- Integrated plugins IDX and MailChimp to allow users to register to website, search the Multiple Listing Service, save favorited properties, and subscribe to newsletters.
- Created pages for helpful resources, client testimonials and past sales.
- Came up with SEO driven blog content and generated more traffic to website.
- Managed Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, and Pinterest accounts.
- Made Facebook ads and installed website pixels to track ads performance and reach.
- Updated email lists and sent out monthly newsletters to subscribers with valuable researched content.

ASSISTANT TO TOP PRODUCING TEAM

Keller Williams II Santa Monica II 2013 - 2015

- Worked on a team of 4 and oversaw all aspects of buyer and seller transactions from executed purchase agreement to closing.
- Opened escrows, developed and implemented systems for sellers, buyers, client database management, lead follow up, and all office administration to ensure an organized and smooth transaction.
- Coordinate inspections, assisted in negotiations regarding repairs, and coordinated completion of repairs.
- Regularly updated & maintained communication with clients, agents, title officer, lender.
- Excelled at building trusting relationships with clients and colleagues. Provided proactive weekly feedback to sellers regarding all showings and marketing activities.
- Assisted with marketing by providing market updates with information from the Multiple Listings Service.
- Proficient with Zipforms, Microsoft Office, Outlook, Photoshop, the MLS, and Top Producer.